[    
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la lámina",
    "back" : "sheet, plate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "tragarse",
    "back" : "to swallow"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la fiera",
    "back" : "beast"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "trazar",
    "back" : "to trace, to draw"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "asustarse",
    "back" : "to get scared"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la obra maestra",
    "back" : "masterpiece"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "digerir",
    "back" : "to digest, to assimilate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "desalentarse",
    "back" : "to get discouraged"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el fracaso",
    "back" : "failure, collapse"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "extraviarse",
    "back" : "to get lost, to go astray"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la avería",
    "back" : "breakdown, damage"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el náufrago",
    "back" : "a shipwrecked person"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "frotar",
    "back" : "to rub, to scrub"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el retrato",
    "back" : "portrait, picture"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "absorto",
    "back" : "absorbed, engrossed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "asombro",
    "back" : "astonishment"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "rehacer",
    "back" : "to remake, to redo"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "garabatear",
    "back" : "to scribble, doodle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el rostro",
    "back" : "face, image"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "acosar",
    "back" : "to harass"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el azar",
    "back" : "chance, fate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la carcajada",
    "back" : "loud laugh, guffaw"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "entrever",
    "back" : "to glimpse, to catch sight of"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "menear",
    "back" : "to shake"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "hundir",
    "back" : "to sink, to submerge"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el ensueño",
    "back" : "daydream, fantasy, illusion"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el tesoro",
    "back" : "treasure"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "abismarse",
    "back" : "to be engulfed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "esforzarse",
    "back" : "to make an effort"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la cuerda",
    "back" : "rope"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "atar",
    "back" : "to tie up"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la estaca",
    "back" : "stake, post"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el estallido",
    "back" : "explosion, outbreak"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "apenas",
    "back" : "hardly; scarcely"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la cifra",
    "back" : "figure, number"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "acertar",
    "back" : "to guess correctly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "encoger",
    "back" : "to shrink, shrug"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "reprochar",
    "back" : "to blame, to criticise"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "indulgente",
    "back" : "lenient, tolerant"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "burlar",
    "back" : "to evade, to outwit"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el hada/las hadas",
    "back" : "fairy/fairies"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "penoso",
    "back" : "horrible, pitiful"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "vacilar",
    "back" : "to hesitate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "semajante",
    "back" : "similar"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "envejecer",
    "back" : "to grow old, to age"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "asaltar",
    "back" : "to attack, to assault"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la semilla",
    "back" : "seed, origin"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "estirar",
    "back" : "to stretch"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "estallar",
    "back" : "to burst"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "arrancar",
    "back" : "to pull out"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "descuidar",
    "back" : "to neglect"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "acechar",
    "back" : "to stalk, to spy on"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la puesta del sol",
    "back" : "sunset"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "bastar",
    "back" : "to be enough, to suffice"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el crepúsculo",
    "back" : "twilight, dusk"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "destornillar",
    "back" : "to unscrew"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el bulón",
    "back" : "bolt"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "agotar",
    "back" : "to exhaust, to use up"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "largar",
    "back" : "to release, to let out"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "rencor",
    "back" : "resentment"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "martillazo",
    "back" : "a hit with a hammer"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "avergonzar",
    "back" : "to embarrass"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "despiadado",
    "back" : "ruthless, merciless"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sacudir",
    "back" : "to shake, to dust"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aspirar",
    "back" : "to aspire"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "restar",
    "back" : "to subtract, to deduct"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el hongo",
    "back" : "fungus"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aniquilar",
    "back" : "annihilate, exterminate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enrojecer",
    "back" : "to blush"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sollozar",
    "back" : "to sob"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la herramienta",
    "back" : "tool"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "acunar",
    "back" : "to rock, to cradle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el bozal",
    "back" : "muzzle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "torpe",
    "back" : "clumsy, awkward"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "extinguirse",
    "back" : "to become extinct"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cesar",
    "back" : "to cease"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el capullo",
    "back" : "bud"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "milagrosa",
    "back" : "miraculous"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "embellecer",
    "back" : "to embellish"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ajustar",
    "back" : "to adjust"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la arruga",
    "back" : "wrinkle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la amapola",
    "back" : "poppy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el resplandor",
    "back" : "brightness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "coqueto",
    "back" : "flirtatious"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ataviar",
    "back" : "to dress up"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "bostezar",
    "back" : "to yawn"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "conmovedor",
    "back" : "moving, touching"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "advirtir",
    "back" : "to warn"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la bondad",
    "back" : "kindness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la regadera",
    "back" : "watering can"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sombrío",
    "back" : "somber"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el biombo",
    "back" : "screen"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "meterse",
    "back" : "to get into"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "humillar",
    "back" : "to humiliate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "infligir",
    "back" : "to inflict"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "remordimiento",
    "back" : "remorse"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la voluntad",
    "back" : "will, willpower"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "gozar",
    "back" : "to enjoy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "fastidiar",
    "back" : "to annoy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enternecer",
    "back" : "to soften, to move (emotionally)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el huido",
    "back" : "fugitive"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "deshollinar",
    "back" : "to chimney sweep"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "arder",
    "back" : "to burn"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la partida",
    "back" : "departure"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "disgustar",
    "back" : "to dislike"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el brote",
    "back" : "outbreak, sprout"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cotidiano",
    "back" : "daily"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "regar",
    "back" : "to water"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el resfriado",
    "back" : "cold (illness)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "procurar",
    "back" : "to be able to, to obtain, to get"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la ausencia",
    "back" : "absence"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "mansedumbre",
    "back" : "docility, gentleness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "proseguir",
    "back" : "to proceed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la oruga",
    "back" : "caterpillar"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ingenua",
    "back" : "naive"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "instruirse",
    "back" : "to improve oneself"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el armiño",
    "back" : "stoat"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el manto",
    "back" : "cape"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "exigir",
    "back" : "to demand"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el faldón",
    "back" : "shirttail"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "apresurarse",
    "back" : "to hurry"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "atreverse/osar",
    "back" : "to dare"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "reposar",
    "back" : "to rest"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "arrojarse",
    "back" : "to throw oneself"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "indagar",
    "back" : "to inquire"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la carroza",
    "back" : "carriage, parade float"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "asomarse",
    "back" : "to peek"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "opuesto",
    "back" : "opposite"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sabio",
    "back" : "knowledgeable"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "condenar",
    "back" : "to condemn"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "afligir",
    "back" : "to afflict"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "emprender",
    "back" : "to begin"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aclamar",
    "back" : "to cheer"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la alabanza",
    "back" : "praise (noun)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sumir",
    "back" : "to sink"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "lúgubre",
    "back" : "gloomy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "compadecer",
    "back" : "to sympathise with"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "socorrer",
    "back" : "to help/to rescue"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "encerrar",
    "back" : "to enclose"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "alejarse",
    "back" : "to move away"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "abejorro",
    "back" : "bumblebee"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "desvariar",
    "back" : "to talk nonsense"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el holgazán",
    "back" : "lazy person"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el ebrio",
    "back" : "drunk"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "hosco",
    "back" : "gloomy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "farol",
    "back" : "lantern"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enjuagar",
    "back" : "to rinse"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "fiel",
    "back" : "faithful"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la zancada",
    "back" : "stride"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ajena",
    "back" : "someone else's"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "añorar",
    "back" : "to miss"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "resoplar",
    "back" : "to pant"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "decepcionado",
    "back" : "disappointed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "carecer",
    "back" : "to lack"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el cómputo",
    "back" : "calculation"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ambular",
    "back" : "to move, to rove"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "averiguar",
    "back" : "to find out, to inquire, to investigate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ocasionar",
    "back" : "to cause"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "súbitamente",
    "back" : "suddenly, unexpectedly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "afinar",
    "back" : "to tune"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "suministrar",
    "back" : "to supply"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "amenzar",
    "back" : "to threaten"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el conjunto",
    "back" : "band, group"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el ejército",
    "back" : "army"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la danza",
    "back" : "dance"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "escabullir",
    "back" : "to sneak, to slip away"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ocioso",
    "back" : "idle, lazy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "agradar",
    "back" : "to please, to be pleasing (to like something)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el navío",
    "back" : "ship"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enroscarse",
    "back" : "to coil, to twist"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cortésmente",
    "back" : "courteously"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el taburete",
    "back" : "stool"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la aguja",
    "back" : "needle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "afilado",
    "back" : "sharp"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "puntiagudo",
    "back" : "pointed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la morada",
    "back" : "dwelling, home"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "desdichado",
    "back" : "unhappy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "vejado",
    "back" : "vexed, annoyed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aparentar",
    "back" : "to pretend"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el manzano",
    "back" : "apple tree"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el fusil",
    "back" : "rifle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "criar",
    "back" : "to raise, to bring up, to rear"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el lazo",
    "back" : "bond, tie"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "madriguera",
    "back" : "burrow"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el trigo",
    "back" : "wheat"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "callar",
    "back" : "to shut up"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "reojo",
    "back" : "sideways glance"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el rito",
    "back" : "ritual"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "fijo",
    "back" : "permanent"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el transeúnte",
    "back" : "passer-by, pedestrian"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "quejarse",
    "back" : "to complain"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "alabarse",
    "back" : "to brag"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "rugir",
    "back" : "to roar"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el trueno (tronar)",
    "back" : "thunder"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el vidrio",
    "back" : "glass (material)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aplastar",
    "back" : "to crush"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la píldora",
    "back" : "pill"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aplacar",
    "back" : "to appease"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "medir",
    "back" : "measure"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el pozo",
    "back" : "water well"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el gesto",
    "back" : "gesture"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cansancio",
    "back" : "tiredness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el fiebre",
    "back" : "fever"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el pliegue",
    "back" : "fold"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "resplandecer",
    "back" : "to shine"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el fondo",
    "back" : "bottom"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cargar",
    "back" : "to carry/load/charge"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el agujero, el hueco, el roto",
    "back" : "hole (opening)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el agujero, el hoyo",
    "back" : "hole (in the ground)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "cavar",
    "back" : "to dig"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la aldea",
    "back" : "village"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la roldana/polea",
    "back" : "pulley"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el balde",
    "back" : "bucket"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "gimir",
    "back" : "to moan"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la veleta",
    "back" : "weather vane"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "izar",
    "back" : "to hoist, to raise"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la misa",
    "back" : "mass (religious)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la dulzura",
    "back" : "sweetness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "apenarse",
    "back" : "to feel sorrow"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el bosquejo",
    "back" : "sketch"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el repollo",
    "back" : "cabbage"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "oprimir",
    "back" : "to oppress"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "colgar",
    "back" : "to hang"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el veneno",
    "back" : "poison, venom"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el brinco, el salto",
    "back" : "jump"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "erguir",
    "back" : "to raise, to stand up straight"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aflojar",
    "back" : "to loosen up"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "latir",
    "back" : "to beat"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "escurrir",
    "back" : "to drain"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el cascabel",
    "back" : "bell/rattle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "inquieto",
    "back" : "restless"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la mordedura",
    "back" : "bite (wound)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la corteza",
    "back" : "bark, peel"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enmohecido",
    "back" : "mouldy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el relámpago",
    "back" : "lightning bolt"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ni siquiera",
    "back" : "not even"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "camarada",
    "back" : "comrade"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la correa",
    "back" : "leash"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "colocar",
    "back" : "to place"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "silenciosamente",
    "back" : "silently"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la fuerza",
    "back" : "force, strength"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el pariente",
    "back" : "relative"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la facilidad",
    "back" : "ease"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la liviandad",
    "back" : "frivolity, lightness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la enseñanza",
    "back" : "(a) teaching, lesson"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la sabiduría",
    "back" : "knowledge, wisdom"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "internarse",
    "back" : "to send in/to get into"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "alcanzar",
    "back" : "to reach, to attain"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el sembrado",
    "back" : "cultivated field"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el guerrero",
    "back" : "warrior"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la venida",
    "back" : "arrival"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la hembra",
    "back" : "female"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "con anterioridad, con anticipación",
    "back" : "prior"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "forastero",
    "back" : "foreigner, outsider"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "espantar",
    "back" : "to frighten (animals, to spook)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la presa",
    "back" : "prey"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "disimulo",
    "back" : "slyness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "complacer",
    "back" : "to please, to satisfy (someone's needs)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "descabellado",
    "back" : "ridiculous"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "herido",
    "back" : "wounded"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el hueco",
    "back" : "hole"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la cúpula",
    "back" : "dome"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el arco",
    "back" : "arch, bow (weapon)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el barrote",
    "back" : "bar (of a window or a prison cell)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "volcar",
    "back" : "to knock over"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sordo",
    "back" : "deaf"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "despegar",
    "back" : "to take off (plane)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "desviar",
    "back" : "to divert"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el alero",
    "back" : "eave (of a roof)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el acantilado",
    "back" : "cliff"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la destreza",
    "back" : "skill"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "trepar",
    "back" : "to climb"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "clavar",
    "back" : "to drive, to stab"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "apenas",
    "back" : "hardly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "enredar",
    "back" : "to mess with, to tangle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "empapado",
    "back" : "soaked"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "hediondo",
    "back" : "smelly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "empañar",
    "back" : "to dull, to mist"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el caucho, la goma",
    "back" : "rubber"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el desperdicio",
    "back" : "waste, remains"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el rastro",
    "back" : "trail, trace"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el huésped",
    "back" : "guest"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "asustar",
    "back" : "to frighten, to scare"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "blando",
    "back" : "soft, lenient"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "empeñado",
    "back" : "determined, stubborn"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la pista",
    "back" : "track, sign, clue"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aturdido",
    "back" : "stunned, dazed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ello",
    "back" : "it"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "espesar",
    "back" : "to thicken"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el sudor",
    "back" : "sweat"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la choza",
    "back" : "hut, shack"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el capataz",
    "back" : "foreman, boss"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "entregar",
    "back" : "to deliver"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el estrépito",
    "back" : "crash, racket"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el lagarto",
    "back" : "lizard, alligator"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aletargado",
    "back" : "lethargic, sluggish"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el rocío",
    "back" : "spray, mist, dew"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el vello",
    "back" : "hair (body)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el palo",
    "back" : "stick, club"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "pulido",
    "back" : "polished"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la mejilla",
    "back" : "cheek (of face)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "morado",
    "back" : "purple"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la costilla",
    "back" : "rib"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "en cuclillas",
    "back" : "to squat, to crouch"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "antes que nada",
    "back" : "first of all"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "gastar",
    "back" : "to spend, to waste"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "malgastar",
    "back" : "to waste, to spend badly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "semanal",
    "back" : "weekly"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el sorbo",
    "back" : "sip, gulp"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "echar",
    "back" : "to throw, to pour, to put"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el chorro",
    "back" : "stream, jet, spurt"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "por desgracia",
    "back" : "unfortunately"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "dañar",
    "back" : "to damage, to harm"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "expiación",
    "back" : "purification, atonement"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "mentar",
    "back" : "to mention (something negative, taboo)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el vientre, la barriga",
    "back" : "abdomen"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el miembro",
    "back" : "member, limb"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el aliento",
    "back" : "breath/encouragement"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el suspiro",
    "back" : "sigh, breath"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aferrar",
    "back" : "to grasp, to cling to"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el esternón",
    "back" : "sternum"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la torpeza",
    "back" : "clumsiness, awkwardness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "torpe",
    "back" : "clumsy, awkward"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el mentón, la barbilla",
    "back" : "chin"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la pila",
    "back" : "pile, stack; battery"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la paja",
    "back" : "straw, hay"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la hoguera",
    "back" : "bonfire, fire"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "arrastrar",
    "back" : "to drag"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el imán",
    "back" : "magnet"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la ala",
    "back" : "wing"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "mugriento",
    "back" : "filthy, greasy"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el alta",
    "back" : "discharge (from a hospital)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "lidiar",
    "back" : "to deal with"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "fingir",
    "back" : "to pretend, to fake"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el erizo",
    "back" : "hedgehog"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "erizar",
    "back" : "to stand on end"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "aguantar",
    "back" : "to endure, to tolerate"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el somnífero",
    "back" : "sleeping pill"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la jornada",
    "back" : "working day, day trip (activity for the day)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el difunto",
    "back" : "deceased person"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "desprender",
    "back" : "to detach"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el hígado",
    "back" : "liver"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "hallar",
    "back" : "to find, to discover (without necessarily trying)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el bocado",
    "back" : "bite, morsel (of food)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "podrida",
    "back" : "rotten"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "revolcar",
    "back" : "to roll around"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el barro",
    "back" : "mud"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la rama",
    "back" : "tree branch"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la desdicha",
    "back" : "misfortune, unhappiness"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ceniza",
    "back" : "ash"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "machacado",
    "back" : "crushed, mashed"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la ciruela",
    "back" : "plum"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la acelga",
    "back" : "silver beet"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la guinda",
    "back" : "cherry"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el girasol",
    "back" : "sunflower"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "tasar",
    "back" : "to value (measure, compare)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la lija",
    "back" : "sandpaper"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la sandía",
    "back" : "watermelon"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el durasno",
    "back" : "peach"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el damasco, el albaricoque",
    "back" : "apricot"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el dado",
    "back" : "dice"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la albahaca",
    "back" : "basil"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "descargarse",
    "back" : "to run down (batteries), to rant"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el pan rallado",
    "back" : "bread crumbs"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la mecha",
    "back" : "wick, fuse"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sutil",
    "back" : "subtle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "burlar",
    "back" : "to make fun of"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "ahorcar",
    "back" : "to hang, to strangle"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la portada",
    "back" : "front page, cover"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la pauta",
    "back" : "guideline, pattern, model"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "lo de menos",
    "back" : "the least of it"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "pelear",
    "back" : "to fight, to argue"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "corporal",
    "back" : "of the body"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "sanar",
    "back" : "to cure, to heal"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "fijar",
    "back" : "to fix, to focus, to attach"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "tropezar",
    "back" : "to trip (fall)"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "el manicomio",
    "back" : "asylum, mental hospital"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la manía",
    "back" : "obsession, fixation"
    },
    {
    "id": 0,
    "SRI": 1,
    "front": "la desliz",
    "back" : "(a) slip up"
    }
]